Gaurav Borra

Product Designer

+91-7838000558 gauravborra@gmail.com

Summary

I bring a unique perspective to the design process. My skills are centered around human-computer interactions, allow me to create delightful experiences that solve complex problems through a data-driven approach.

I can take an idea to concept to wireframe to prototype to development.

Portfolio

behance.net/gauravborra gauravborra.com

Work Experience

Classplus

Feb 2022 - Present

Senior Product Designer

Classplus is a ed-tech company working on B2B model which have an extensive products. As a product designer, my role here is to make product's better in users experience so that our users (educators) can focus on teaching and we handle the rest. Along with that i also help my team to streamline process to reduce time & effort.

Snapdeal

April 2019 - Jan 2022

Senior Product Designer

As a Product Designer at Snapdeal, I am helping the growth & Product Management to solve the problems. I am responsible for taking product features from problem identification to high fidelity specifications. I work closely with our researchers to identify user needs and validate prototypes, while also aiding our development team to implement our designs.

Scicomm.in

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Head of Design

As a Design Head at Scicomm, I did a complete revamp of their visual identity. I created their Brand Identity and defined their design styles & guides which included their Brand Logo, website design, printables etc. It helped the brand to drive new business and create a brand awareness.

Paytm

April 2015 -Sep 2017

Creative Designer

As a Creative Designer, i was leading the design team in making visual designs for special marketing campaigns through designing banners, Illustrations, web designs and social media posts. I also did their classic iconography.

Education

GGSIPU

2010 - 2014

B.Tech, Computer Science

Learned software life cycle including need of requirement gathering techniques such as research, brainstorming, prototyping, development and testing.

CBSE

2009

Intermediate, 10+2

Passed Intermediate as a science student from ASN Senior Secondary School.

CBSE

2007

High School

Passed high school from ASN Senior Secondary School.

Awards

Winner

2020

Snap-a-thon

Won annual product development competition at Snapdeal as the product designer in a team of six.

We presented a solution to a problem of accesibility within our user base in the form of a voice assistant for e-commerce

Skills

User Interface Design

Interaction Design

Wireframing

Visual Design

Prototyping

User Research

Design Language System

Design Thinking

Animation

Illustrations

Typography

HTML

CSS

Java Script

Tools

Figma

Sketch App

Invison

Adobe XD

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Premiere Pro

Adobe Indesign

Zeplin

Abstract